thekartel.com 2010-12-22

# > Blog Post, thekartel.com

It’s time to get into the juicy stuff. That is, if you like to real long drawn out legal notices and stuff. Hey, don’t knock it. Some people love this stuff. Today’s topic du jour: Privacy.

Here’s the short version:

We’d like to foster a community of trust. We’re pretty up front about what info we collect, and why. Because we are a connected community that partners with various game developers, and other entities, we do allow for them to reach out to you. However, unless other determined by you, we do not share your secrets with them. We would also NEVER ask you for your password, credit card info, phone number, etc. So don’t just go handing it out like a cheap floozie, ok?

Here’s the long version:

This document describes the information gathering, use, and dissemination practices for The Kartel. This Privacy Statement addresses The Kartel’s practices regarding information collected only directly through or from the Site – it does not address or govern any information gathering, use, or dissemination practices related to information collected other than directly through or from the site, including, without limitation, from or via telephone, facsimile, postal mail, personal delivery, or other or additional offline means or media. California and Canadian residents have the right to know how their information may be shared with third parties who engage in direct marketing activities and this Privacy Statement explains our practices and how you can opt-out of having your information shared for such purposes.

**Information Collection**

The Kartel may collect or track (1) the e-mail addresses of visitors that communicate with The Kartel via e-mail, and (2) information knowingly provided by the visitor in online forms, registration forms, forums, surveys, contests, polls, e-mail, the “Contact Us” section of the site, and other online avenues (including, without limitation, demographic, interests, behavior, and personal profile data), (3) the home server domain names, e-mail addresses, IP addresses, type of client computer, files downloaded, search engine used, operating system, and type of Web browser of visitors to the site and persons responding to polls, and (4) aggregate and visitor-specific information regarding which pages visitors access. For example:

·         **Registration**

In order to submit content or participate in the community forums on the site, sign up for and/or use The Kartel services, a visitor may be asked to first complete a registration form. During registration a visitor may be required to give their contact information (such as name and email address). 

·         **Information Collected Via Log Files And Cookies**

While a visitor is on the site, The Kartel automatically tracks certain information through log files and, on some pages, through cookies (a cookie is a piece of data stored on the visitor's hard drive containing information about the visitor) or Web bugs (a Web “bug” is a file object, which can be a graphic image such as a transparent one pixel-by-one pixel graphics file, which is placed on a Web page or in an e-mail message to monitor user activity). This information may include data regarding a visitor’s most recent visit, the URL they came from, the URL they visit next, the browser they are using, and their IP address. The Kartel evaluates this data on an aggregate basis and does not associate the information with a visitor’s personal identity. 

·         **Newsletter**

By registering, a visitor agrees to sign up for the newsletter, which is sent out periodically. The Kartel presents the option to opt-out at any time.

·         **Surveys, Polls, & Contests**

From time-to-time our site requests information from visitors via surveys, polls, contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions, either sponsored by The Kartel or one of its business partners. Participation in these surveys, contests, or polls is completely voluntary and the visitor therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose any information (although, for example, mailing address and demographic information may be required to enter contests). Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). 

·         **Tell-A-Friend**

If a visitor elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, The Kartel asks them for the friend's name and email address. 

·         **Special Offers**

The Kartel sends all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our visitors The Kartel presents the option to opt-out of these emails.

**Use of Information**

Personal data collected by The Kartel may be used by The Kartel for many reasons, for example, for editorial and feedback purposes, for marketing and promotional purposes, such as to deliver advertisements and promotions targeted to our visitor’s interests, for a statistical analysis of visitors’ behavior, for product development, for content improvement, to deliver promotional information from The Kartel or its sponsors provided the visitor opted in for these notifications, to contact a visitor, or to customize the content and layout of the site. Aggregate visitor data may be used for internal purposes, and individually identifying information, such as names, postal and e-mail addresses, phone numbers, and other personal information which visitors voluntarily provide to The Kartel may be added to The Kartel’s databases and used for future calls, mailings, and other communications regarding updates of site, new products and services, and upcoming events. Aggregate visitor data may be provided to marketing firms and other organizations that provide marketing and/or marketing support services to The Kartel.

In addition, registration information may be used to contact the visitor about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. For example, if you win some cool stuff in our swag auction (congrats!), we’ll use your profile info to contact and notify you.  Survey and poll information may be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of the site, and as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Statement. Tell-A-Friend information may be used by The Kartel to send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site (The Kartel stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email). Information collected via cookies or Web bugs may be used to analyze trends, administer the site, track visitor's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

**Disclosure of Information**

Data may be disclosed or distributed (1) to another party with which The Kartel enters or reasonably may enter into a corporate transaction, such as, for example, a merger, consolidation, acquisition, or asset purchase, (2) to a third party (a) pursuant to a subpoena, court order, or other form of legal process, (b) in response to a request by or on behalf of any local, state, federal, or other government agency, department, or body, whether or not pursuant to a subpoena, court order, or other form of legal process, or (c) if determined by The Kartel in its sole judgment that such disclosure or distribution is appropriate to protect the life, health, rights, or property of The Kartel or any other person or entity, or (3) as necessary to third parties under contract with The Kartel to improve and provide services associated with the site. In situations involving bankruptcy or insolvency, the database containing personal data may be treated as an asset of The Kartel. Identifiable and non-identifiable visitor information and data which visitors provide to The Kartel also may be provided to third parties that provide products, information, or services which The Kartel believes that visitors may be interested in directly or indirectly purchasing or obtaining. 

While The Kartel may undertake efforts to see that any third party to or with which The Kartel shares, rents, sells, or otherwise discloses personal data is under a contractual obligation to use the personal data solely for the purposes for which the data was disclosed, The Kartel is not responsible for their conduct, actions, omissions, or information handling or dissemination practices and The Kartel will not be liable therefore. 

**Choice/Opt-out**

Except as necessary for The Kartel to provide the services, information, or products requested by a visitor, the visitor may opt out of having his or her personally identifiable information, which has been voluntarily provided to The Kartel through an online form, registration form, forum, survey, contest, poll, the “Contact Us” section of the site, or other similar mechanism, prospectively retained by The Kartel, used by The Kartel for secondary purposes, or disclosed by The Kartel to third parties by updating your information at the member information page or contacting The Kartel via postal mail, e-mail, facsimile, or telephone at the address or numbers set out above. Once The Kartel has implemented the visitor’s request, The Kartel will prospectively cease retaining, using for secondary purposes, or disclosing to third parties the personally identifiable information identified by the visitor in his or her request, to the extent directed in the request, except as required by law. (This does not apply to collection of the type of Web browser of the visitor to the site or to information provided or collected that does not meet the above description.)

**Third Party Advertisements, Products, and Services**

Kartel is not responsible for the privacy practices of other Web sites, advertisements for or placed by third parties, and products or services provided by third party business development partners which are provided as links on our site. It is possible that these portions of the site, links, or advertisements, themselves, may be used by third parties or others to collect personal or other information about site visitors. Often, these companies employ cookie and 1x1 pixel/Web bug technology to collect and use anonymous information about your visits to such Web sites and other Web sites to track the performance of an ad program. In addition, The Kartel may use third-party advertising companies and networks to serve ads to you on our behalf when you visit our websites. Both The Kartel and these companies may use information (not including your names, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. It is solely the visitors’ obligation to review and understand the privacy practices and policies of these other Web sites and of these advertisers and third parties. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by other companies, [please visit ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)[](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppi... "http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppi...")[here.](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

**Non-U.S. Users**

If you are located outside of the United States, please note that the information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using this site, you consent to this transfer. You also consent to the adjudication of any disputes arising in connection with the site in the federal and state courts of, and in accordance with the laws of, the state of California.

**Security**

The Kartel has implemented numerous security features designed to prevent the unauthorized release of or access to personal information. Please be advised that the confidentiality of any communication or materials transmitted to or from The Kartel via the site or e-mail cannot be guaranteed. Accordingly, The Kartel is not responsible for the security of information transmitted via the Internet. 

**Children Under 15**

The site must not be used by children under 15. Children under 15 MUST not submit personal information.

**Changes and Updates**

The Kartel may amend this Privacy Statement at any time by posting the amended policy on the site. The amended policy shall automatically take effect 30 days after it is first posted on the site. Continued use of the site after any changes made to this Privacy Statement signifies a visitor’s understanding, intention and agreement to be bound by such change. It is the visitor’s responsibility to monitor this Privacy Statement for changes. Any change to this Privacy Statement shall be effective as to any visitor who has visited the site before the change was made.

This Privacy Statement is effective September 1, 2009.

Copyright© 2009 The Kartel. All rights reserved.
